<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://agentic-community.github.io/blog</id>
    <title>Agentic Community Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-12-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://agentic-community.github.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Agentic Community Blog</subtitle>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Agentic Community: Six Months Together]]></title>
        <id>https://agentic-community.github.io/blog/2025/12/12/</id>
        <link href="https://agentic-community.github.io/blog/2025/12/12/"/>
        <updated>2025-12-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A look back at 2025]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Agentic Community: Six Months Together</p>
<p>The Agentic Community launched on May 21, 2025, convening eighteen organizations to address the emerging challenges of
agentic systems. While the path forward was not entirely defined, there was clear consensus that collaboration across
the industry would be essential.</p>
<p>That inaugural session established the foundation for our work. Representatives from Snowflake, HPE, IBM, Cisco, and AWS
presented their perspectives on the trajectory of agentic systems. A live demonstration of multi-agent collaboration on
EKS using MCP and A2A protocols illustrated the technical possibilities. The substantive work, however, came in the
collaborative sessions where participants aligned on the community's vision, mission, and operational structure. Working
groups were formed and initial priorities established.</p>
<p>The momentum from that first day carried through the following months.</p>
<p>Weekly meetings became the cadence for both the full community and individual working groups. <a href="https://solo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Solo.io</a>
presented their Agent Gateway approach, contributing to the evolving technical dialogue. The community released their
thoughts on
the <a href="https://agentic-community.com/docs/Artifacts/evolving-systems-architecture" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">evolution of systems architecture</a>. The
operations working group developed and published a
reference <a href="https://github.com/agentic-community/wg-operations/tree/main/proposals/0001-reference-architecture" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">architecture for agentic systems</a>,
addressing a critical gap in the ecosystem. The security working group delivered
an <a href="https://agentic-community.com/docs/artifacts/agent-identity-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">identity framework</a> specifically designed for agentic
environments. <a href="https://github.com/agentic-community/wg-operations/tree/main/projects/agent-building-template" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Starter templates</a>
were created to accelerate development and promote consistent practices across implementations.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://github.com/agentic-community/mcp-gateway-registry" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MCP Gateway Registry</a> launched successfully and
continues to expand (integration with Cisco AI Defense, ongoing pilots with several organizations, and Kubernetes
support). A <a href="https://github.com/agentic-community/agentic-on-eks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">demo</a> showcasing multi-agent platforms on EKS using
MCP and A2A was built. Finally, a <a href="https://github.com/awslabs/ai-on-eks/pull/232" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reference implementation</a> of the
community architecture was submitted to <a href="https://awslabs.github.io/ai-on-eks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AI on EKS</a>, demonstrating the practical
application of our collective work.</p>
<p>In six months, we have produced a number of technical artifacts. More significantly, we have established a collaborative
framework where organizations work across traditional competitive boundaries to advance the field. This foundation will
support the work ahead.</p>
<p>While we produced many artifacts, we acknowledge that our priorities changed and some things were not as impactful as we
initially anticipated. In an effort to continuously improve and focus on our community, we are looking to 2026 to adapt
to the ever-changing landscape. To that end, in 2026, we will fold all the working groups into a single meeting. This
will allow us to work more closely together and ensure we stay focused on a common goal. We will continue having our
bi-weekly community meetings to highlight the work we're doing to the larger community, while those who would like to
collaborate more closely are welcome to continue joining the working group meeting on alternating weeks. We will use our
community meetings to discuss specific topics agreed upon in advance. We will update the meeting invite and notes to
include the topic so that we can all prepare for the discussion. Finally, we would like to affirm our commitment to
thought leadership as our north star: there is a wealth of experience to draw from this group and we should strive to
share it with the broader technical community.</p>
<p>We are steadfast in advancing our collective understanding of this fast moving space and continue to believe that,
together, we can make meaningful advances faster.</p>
<p>Have a happy and safe holiday and we'll see you all in the new year.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>